

Portugal

+351 926 843 295

franciscoandre.farp@gmail.com

My Portfolio in ffarps.github.io

My linkedin

OBJECTIVE

My name is Francisco André Rodrigues Pereira, I'm 22 years old, from Mirandela, and I graduated from the Polytechnic Institute of Braganca with a degree in Informatics Engineering.

During the third year of the course and after completing it, I was awarded two research grants by the Centre for Research in Digitalisation and Intelligent Robotics (CeDRI).

Proactive and dedicated, ready to achieve great things.

EXPERIENCE

Fev 2024-Present Full Stack Developer Intern at EDNU.AI

Contributed to the implementation of an AI-powered virtual assistant and provided support in developing an API broker. Played a crucial role in data engineering tasks, ensuring the availability of datasets for training the language model solutions. Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams to optimize the codebase for seamless integration of AI technologies solutions.

Jul 2023-Sep 2023 Research Fellowship at CeDRI

CeDRI, Instituto Politécnico de Bragança

Contributed to an OpenZDM project related to developing a C# and OpenGl-based tool in Unity 3D, that aims to reduce defects in production chains in a car factory in the assembly and body shop zones.

Jul 2022-Jan 2023 Research Fellowship at CeDRI

CeDRI, Instituto Politécnico de Bragança

Worked on developing Augmented Reality (AR) and Virtual Reality (VR) apps in Unity, using different frameworks and tools, such as MRTK, ARCore, Vuforia SDK and ARFoundation.

EDUCATION

Oct 2019-Jul 2023 **Degree in Informatics Engineering** Instituto Politécnico de Braganca

Scientific Areas: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Mathematics, Information Systems. Worked on many projects related to Web Development, Computer Architecture, Networking, 3D Modeling, Machine Learning, Data Structures, SQL and IoT.

2016-2019 **High School Diploma**

Science and technology

Agrupamento de Escolas de Mirandela

LANGUAGES

HARD SKILLS

Portuguese - native **English** - proficient German - rudimentary

Programming: C#, Python, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, etc

Source Control: Git, GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket

Linux and Bash Unity 3D

Databases: SQL and NoSQL

SOFT SKILLS

Self-taught Attention to detail **Technical Writing** Teamwork